{
    "id": "98157fbf73ae4f51bd68d6e109fda12b",
    "title": "Either or Neither | Grammar Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "19c6fba6591546d8a5c7c0a8d532b3ee",
            "title": "Either or Neither | Grammar Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I don't like ....................... of my science teachers.",
                    "description": "Either means one or the other of two people or things.",
                    "answers": [
                        "either",
                        "neither",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "You don't like him, do you? I don't ...........................",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "either",
                        "neither",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Peter isn't here today. Martha isn't ..........................",
                    "description": "After mentioning a negative idea, we can add another negative point by using not .... either. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "either",
                        "neither"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I like ........................... of them.",
                    "description": "Neither means 'not either'. The sentence 'I like neither of them' means the same as the sentence 'I don't like either of them.'",
                    "answers": [
                        "either",
                        "neither"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am ............................ a conservative nor a liberal.",
                    "description": "Note the pattern 'neither...nor'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "either",
                        "neither"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He didn't remember and ........................... did I.",
                    "description": "Neither means not...either. After mentioning a negative idea, we can add another negative point by using not...either or neither.",
                    "answers": [
                        "either",
                        "neither"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "........................... of them invited me so I didn't go.",
                    "description": "Neither means 'not one and not the other of two'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Either",
                        "Neither"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "........................... of them seemed interested in the offer.",
                    "description": "Neither means 'not one and not the other of two'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Neither",
                        "Either"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Mary didn't turn up and ......................... did Ruth.",
                    "description": "Neither can mean 'also not'. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "either",
                        "neither"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "John didn't pass the test, and Peter didn't .............................",
                    "description": "Not either means neither. The clause 'and Peter didn't either' means the same as 'and neither did Peter'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "either",
                        "neither"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He ......................... smiled, spoke, nor looked at me.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "either",
                        "neither"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Alice can't dance and ..............................",
                    "description": "The expression 'can't either' means the same as 'neither can'. Neither means 'not ... either'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Stella can't either",
                        "neither can Stella",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}